Maneesh Balle

+91-9566440195 · Maneeshbhallae@gmail.com · <u>@MyPorfolio.com</u> Arcot, Ranipet, Tamil Nadu.

SAP FIORI/UI5 DEVELOPER

As an accomplished SAP developer with around **2 years of experience at TCS**, I have worked on multiple HANA implementations projects playing a key role in delivering multiple custom UI5 applications, standard app extensions, Gateway architecture and ABAP programming on required areas with a proven track record of providing on-site expertise.

KEY COMPETENCIES

UI-SAPUI/5Fiori

- Custom UI5 developments
- Standard Fiori extensions
- Fiori Role Assignment
- Fiori Launchpad configuration

Gateway & Backend

- Gateway/OData Architecture
- RESTful ABAP programming
- · Annotated CDS designs
- Report & RFC Programming

Core Languages

- JavaScript/jQuery
- HTML/CSS/XML/JSON
- JAVA/C#
- ABAP/SQL

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

TCS - TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICE

SAP-Developer

May 2021 - Present

Client: TATA ADVANCED SYSTEM LIMITED (Indian aerospace manufacturing, military engineering and defense technology company) - HANA Implementation

May 2021 - Dec 2022

Roles & Responsibilities

- Responsible for custom and standard Fiori UI5 application development and OData development, including addressing any related issues from clients.
- Designed UI layouts and used Node.js to build a script that automatically deploys SAPUI5 application to a development, testing, or production environment.
- Using CAP, I defined the data structure of multiple application using a domain-specific language (DSL) in CDS (Core Data Services)
- Understood the data model to design OData entities and Gateway RAP accordingly
- Developed ABAP reports and smart forms per functional specification requirements and converted them to Fiori GUI applications if needed.
- Created workbench workflow-based apps in the PP and MM module, ensuring proper workflow approval and rejection.
- Pioneered tracker report filters based on request number, date, sales order, material, status, etc., streamlining tracking processes.
- Worked on standard and custom Fiori application implementation and Launchpad configuration, including semantic object, roles, catalog, group, and user assignment.
- Structured analytic charts/graphs, such as donut, pie, bar graph, and line graph for multiple tracker-based applications.
- Designed an algorithm to convert PDFs to base 64 and vice versa, streamlining data transfer between gateway, UI, and Hana DB.

• Innovated multiple accounting applications that use QR-code/barcode scanners to scan order, batch, and material information, minimizing manual data entry by users.

Client: Saudi Unified Government Resources Planning - HANA Implementation

Jan 2023 - Present

Roles & Responsibilities

- Designed and created custom UI5 applications and RAP (Restful ABAP programming)
- Developed applications that display adobe forms and report data from ABAP system filters based on notification numbers
- Enhanced standard Fiori apps by adding additional fields and cross-app links using Web IDE
- Communicated with clients regularly to discuss and present the possibilities of Fiori/UI5 developments and enhancements
- Prepared detailed technical specifications (TS) based on app workability and RICEFS for the FI module

TOOLS & IDE USED

- Microsoft visual studio
- Eclipse

- Business application studio
- WEB IDE

- Classic GUI
- BTP Cloud

EDUCATION

Vel Tech Rangarajan Dr. Sagunthala R&D Institute of Science and Technology

Bachelor in Computer science & engineering (Distinction - 8.4 CGPA)

LANGUAGE KNOWN

- English Proficient
- Marathi Proficient (Native)
- Tamil Proficient
- · Hindi Proficient

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- · Android Studio JAVA Mobile app developer
- · Full stack PHP Web developer
- UNITY C# Videogame developer & designer

DECLARATION

I solemnly declare that the information stated above is true and correct to the best of my belief.

B.S.MANEESH